Contact

773-490-5536 (Work)

www.linkedin.com/in/kristen-mikula-aprn-fnp-bc-86919530 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Charge Nurse
Intrepreting ECG
Microsoft Office

Languages

English

Certifications

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Emergency Communications Registered Nurse (ECRN)

Basic Life Support (BLS)

Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS)

Emergency Nurse Pediatric Course (ENPC)

Kristen Mikula, APRN, FNP-BC

Family Nurse Practitioner - Emergency Department at Ann & Robert H. Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago

Chicago, Illinois

Summary

I started my first job as a family nurse practitioner (FNP) in the Emergency Department at Ann & Robert H. Lurie Children's Hospital. Before transitioning to a FNP, I worked as a RN in the same department. Prior to my transition to working in pediatrics, I worked at Northwestern Memorial Hospital in the Emergency Department for close to five years. I have strong analytical skills, capable of multi-tasking, and exceptional communication skills. My personality is welcoming which makes me a great team member of my profession. I'm approachable and willing to help other staff to complete tasks in a sufficient amount of time.

Being part of Northwestern Memorial and Lurie Children's has advanced my career in many ways in the field of emergency nursing. I received my ECRN, TNCC, ENPC and CEN. At Northwestern Memorial, I became a member for two committees: Interdisciplinary Emergency Department Practice Committee (chair) and Nursing Evidence Based and Research (representative). At Lurie Children's, I am a member of the education committee and a Magnet champion. By becoming a committee member, I am able to put my input and suggestions in ways to help improve not only the emergency department but also the hospital in its entirety.

Experience

Ann & Robert H. Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago 3 years 1 month

Family Nurse Practitioner
May 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)
Greater Chicago Area

Emergency Room Registered Nurse July 2017 - May 2019 (1 year 11 months)

Greater Chicago Area

- Responsible for all facets of triage, emergency patient care, inpatient procedures and trauma care for the pediatric population.
- As a Charge nurse, demonstrate awareness of ongoing ED unit needs to provide other team members with leadership and direction for reaching optimal nursing care standards and operations.
- Collaborate with other ED professionals to ensure effective patient care delivery.
- Utilize critical thinking skills to intervene with appropriate interventions for urgent/emergent patient care with acute and chronically ill pediatric patients.
- Preceptor for new hires and BSN/MSN nursing students.
- Magnet Champion for the department.
- Member of the department's education committee.

Northwestern University - The Feinberg School of Medicine Simulation Nurse Instructor - Per Diem 2015 - May 2019 (4 years)

Greater Chicago Area

- Intravenous access training for 3rd year medical students.
- Mock page trials for 4th year medical students.
- Simulation nurse instructor for patient case scenarios

Northwestern Memorial Hospital Staff Nurse May 2012 - April 2017 (5 years)

- **Emergency Department**
- Responsible for all facets of triage, emergency patient care, inpatient procedures and trauma care.
- Initiate stroke, STEMI and trauma level I and II codes.
- Demonstrated awareness of ongoing ED unit needs as a relief Charge Nurse to provide other team members with leadership and direction for reaching optimal nursing care standards.
- Utilized critical thinking skills to intervene with appropriate interventions for urgent/emergent patient care with acute and chronically ill adult patients.
- Collaborated with other ED professionals to ensure effective patient care delivery.
- Established peripheral ultrasound guided intravenous lines.
- Representative for Nursing Research and Evidence-Based Practice Committee.
- Chair of Interdisciplinary Emergency Department Practice Committee.

- Preceptor for new hires and BSN/MSN nursing students.
- Represented department during nursing fair.

Resurrection Health Care Staff Nurse May 2011 - May 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Medical-Surgical/Telemetry

- Coordinated admissions, transfers, and discharges of patients for a 40-bed unit.
- Proficient in interpreting EKG readings and labs.
- Monitored drainage devices, chest tubes, medication drips, and pacer wires.
- Managed and documented care and therapies for 4-7 patients per shift.
- Educated patients and families regarding plan of care.
- Coordinated patient care and health status with a multidisciplinary team.
- Preceptor for BSN nursing students and new-hires.
- Charge Nurse during night shift.

Education

Olivet Nazarene University

Master's of Nursing, Family Nurse Practitioner · (2014 - 2017)

Resurrection University

Bachelor of Science, Nursing · (2009 - 2011)